JULIANA SCHEIL

470-214-8009 | JULIANA.M.SCHEIL@GMAIL.COM

GITHUB: HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/JULESSCHEIL | LINKEDIN: WWW.LINKEDIN.COM/IN/JULIANA-SCHEIL

SUMMARY

Highly motivated Data & Analytics specialist with over one year of experience working with people and bridging the gap between data and business strategy. Looking to learn and grow in the Data Analytics space, fueled by a passion for numbers, data correlation, presentation, and visualization utilizing technology such as Tableau. Dedicated with strong leadership skills and proficient in developing strong relationships. Areas of interest include: visualization | data generation | data management | statistics | numerical computing.

EXPERIENCE

PricewaterhouseCoopers

September 2018 – Present

Data & Analytics Technology Consultant

Atlanta, GA

- Performed as an analyst on projects in the business strategy arena, analyzing business structures and operations
- Analyzed client data to determine strategy on domestic and international operational efficiencies
- Prepared presentations for and held status update meetings with client executives
- Met reporting needs alongside an ERP implementation using Excel, SQL, and Tableau
- Managed administrative aspects of projects, including budgeting, client expectations, milestones, and fulfillment of deliverables
- Performed project management duties
- Supervised offshore team members working towards deliverables
- Conducted interviews & workshops to gather information around the current state of business intelligence, including dashboards, reporting capabilities, databases, and tool & technology
- Evaluated current state and recommended future state BI architecture, executive dashboards, and KPI's

Metris Technologies

May 2016 - December 2016

Visualization & Data Analyst

Atlanta, GA

- Developed Tableau dashboards for clients highlighting KPIs and requested metrics
- Tracked inventory, defects, and operational / usage metrics in MS Access, Excel, and MS SQL Server
- Assembled and configured digital video players to display signage throughout hospitals

University of North Carolina at Charlotte

July 2015 - May 2018

Teaching Assistant - Calculus 1 & Pre-Calculus Lead

Charlotte, NC

- Developed automated grading tools for professors utilizing MS Excel, Macros, Pivot Tables, etc.
- Assisted department faculty in teaching undergraduate mathematics courses prepared/reviewed lectures
- Developed lesson plans in MS PowerPoint to teach five classes per week for groups of 20+ students
- Held weekly office hours to provide tutoring, counseling, and assistance to over 120 students
- Designed and developed worksheets and other course content utilizing MS Word and Excel

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE AND PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

PILOT Leadership and Organizational Training

- Participated in numerous trainings such as Time Management and Pain-Free Presenting skills
- Intersection of Faith and Leadership workshop

EDUCATION

University of North Carolina at Charlotte

August 2014 – May 2018

Bachelor of Arts in Business Mathematics; Minor in Women's and Gender Studies

GPA: 3.68/4.0

University of Otago, New Zealand

January 2017 – June 2017

Rigorous coursework in Mathematics, Human – Computer Interactions, and User Experience

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS AND RELEVANT COURSEWORK

Tableau Desktop

Alteryx

UX Design and Heuristics

SQL Server

SAS

Statistical Analysis

- Data Exploration and Generation
- **Operations Research**

MS Office Suite